Artur Trifonov _ Product UI Designer

I have been working in web development and design since 2011. I specialize in creating interfaces and design systems with detailed documentation. For the last 3 years, I have been developing analytics and cloud management services for fintech companies in the top 3 in the country.

Additionally, I have worked as a mentor, written articles and educational materials for design and web development courses, and co-authored a course on design.

I have also delivered offline and online lectures.

in linkedin.com/in/arturtrifonov

Bē behance.net/arturtrifonov

dribbble.com/arturtrifonov

Bratislava, Slovakia

+421 944 616 289

arturtrifonov.com

Languages

- Russian, native
- English, B1

Skills

- Design systems, UI kit
- Prototypes
- Mapping (blueprint, swimlane)
- Technical specification writing
- Design documentation
- Market and audience analysis
- Project management
- Client communication
- Training and mentoring
- Article writing and lecturing

Instruments

- Figma, Sketch
- FigJam
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- ChatGPT
- DALL-E, Midjourney

Education

- Designing and Describing User Behavior in Interface Design Line PRO | 2022
- JavaScript. Architecture of Front-end Applications .html academy | 2021
- Fundamentals of User Centered Design IMPRO | 2013
- Digital Strategist '13/1 IKRA | 2013
- Environmental Design, Specialist1 Pushkin Leningrad State | 2011 University, Faculty of Arts

Experience

CloudTech __ UI / UX Designer

August 2021 - Present

CloudTech creates resource management and planning services for cloud systems, as well as customizable cost reports and optimization recommendations.

- Researching the competitive market and audience, creating blueprint, swimlane, and user experience maps;
- Creating layouts and preparing guidelines;
- Developing and maintaining design systems;
- Collaborating with the development team to ensure design consistency;
- Conducting usability audits, collecting and analyzing feedback.
- **Achievements** Developed a budget and resource expense analytics tool similar to Azure Cost Management, AWS Cost Explorer, and Harness;
 - Created a design system with extensive theming capabilities, advocated for its implementation, which sped up development and increased consistency;
 - Designed several interfaces from scratch, using both my own and external design systems;
 - Participated in the hiring process of personnel.

.html academy __ Author, Mentor

October 2019 - July 2023

HTML Academy is a school with a deep specialization in frontend development, focused on teaching students from scratch.

Achievements

 Assisting students in learning frontend basics, reviewing homework, and providing consultations;

 Writing articles, creating screencasts, and code reviews.

 Conducted 15 intensive courses, teaching 50 students. 30% of students rated the courses 10 out of 10, and 66% successfully completed their projects, which is above average;

- Wrote 9 articles for the textbook and 2 blog posts. Developed a reference project and its review;
- Delivered an open lesson on YouTube about Figma;
- Co-authored the course "Design for Frontenders".

Freelance __ Designer, Frontend developer

June 2019 - August 2021

I worked with clients on a project basis and on support contracts. I developed design and frontend for websites of companies in industrial equipment, automation, security, consulting, and online stores.

Development and design of websites from scratch;

Support and enhancement of existing websites;

- Interaction with clients to gather requirements and agree on designs;
- Integration of design with frontend development.
- Successfully completed 15+ projects (corporate websites, online stores, and landing pages);
- Websites met accessibility requirements (a11y);
- Optimized website performance, achieving scores of 85-95 on Google PageSpeed Insights.

Project examples

- Sensormatica sensormatica.ru
- Peach Bear peach-bear.ru
- NSE Russia nserussia.org
- Koike koike-russia.ru
- Farmavet arturtrifonov.com/portfolio/farmavet

United Design Studio _ Developer, Co-founder

June 2011 – June 2019

A small design studio specializing in web development and branding. Competed with large agencies and actively participated in the development of the design community in Saint-Petersburg.

 Led a development team consisting of a designer, frontend developer, and backend developer;

Created prototypes and managed products.

- Briefed clients and prepared technical specifications;
- **Achievements**
- Implemented the Zurb Foundation UI library, speeding up the development process;
 - Developed a web-based template for successful tender presentations.

Mv Articles and Presentations

- Basics of Figma for Frontend Devs arturtrifonov.com/videos/ figma
- Why should a dev know design? htmlacademy.ru/blog/middle/

frontend-in-design

- □ Modern IT Technologies arturtrifonov.com/videos/it
- Git Workflow, Why Are You So Weird? articles.arturtrifonov.com/ articles/git-workflow
- Modern Layout Techniques arturtrifonov.com/videos/ layout

articles/height-in-css

- When Is Fixed Height How to Load Fonts Needed in Layout? articles.arturtrifonov.com/
- □ Content Management Systems arturtrifonov.com/videos/cms
 - articles.arturtrifonov.com/ articles/include-fonts
- How to Distinguish Margin from Padding articles.arturtrifonov.com/ articles/margin-vs-padding

How to fix common

design mistakes

bad-design

htmlacademy.ru/blog/articles/